Lowell Thomas Papers: Objects
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 8. Miscellany, 8; Boxes: 1724 - 1743
  - Subseries 8.2: Printing plates, 1933 - 1941; 8.2; Boxes: 1728 - 1730
    - Subseries 8.2.4: Kabluk of the Eskimo, 1932; 8.2.4; Boxes: 1739
      - Kabluk of the Eskimo: Lowell Thomas. This print contains an Eskimo hunting a bear as well as an Eskimo in a canoe. Lowell Thomas’s name appears in the upper corner. Measures 7½ x 7½ inches, 1932 (Folder 1, Box 1739)
      - Kabluk of the Eskimo: Lowell Thomas. This print contains an Eskimo a hunting bear. Also shown is an iceberg. Measures 7½ x 7½ inches, 1932 (Folder 2, Box 1739)
      - Kabluk of the Eskimo: Lowell Thomas. Measures 9 x 6 inches, 1932 (Folder 3, Box 1739)
      - Eskimo hunting scene. Measures 6 x 7½ inches, 1932 (Folder 4, Box 1739)
      - Eskimo village scene. Measures 4¼ x 6¼ inches, 1932 (Folder 5, Box 1739)
      - A person dressed in Eskimo attire. [circular plate] Wooden block measures 3¼ x 6¼ inches, 1932 (Folder 6, Box 1739)
      - Boys’ edition Kabluk of the Eskimo: Lowell Thomas. Measures 6¾ x 2½ inches, 1932 (Folder 7, Box 1739)
      - Kabluk of the Eskimo: Lowell Thomas. Measures 7 x 2½ inches, 1932 (Folder 8, Box 1739)
      - Kabluk of the Eskimo: Lowell Thomas. Measures 5¾ x 2½ inches, 1932 (Folder 9, Box 1739)
      - Plate reads: Kabluk of the Eskimo: Lowell Thomas. [2 copies] One plate measures 2 x 1¼ inches; the other 2 x 4¼ inches, 1932 (Folder 10, Box 1739)
    - Subseries 8.2.5: Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1946; 8.2.5; Box: 1740
      - Bikini and a Flight Around the World lecture circular. Measures 11¾ x 15¾ inches, 1946 (Folder 1, Box 1740)
    - Subseries 8.2.6: Literary Digest, 1931; 8.2.6; Box: 1741
      - Printing plate for the cover of Literary Digest (Lowell Thomas is seated next to a globe). [6 copies] Four measure 10¼ x 9 inches and two measure 8¾ x 9 inches, 1931 September 19 (Folder 1-6, Box 1741)
    - Subseries 8.2.7: Miscellany, 8.2.7; Boxes: 1742 - 1743
      - Correspondence from Lowell Thomas to Mr. Leland. Measures 6 x 4½ inches, 1962 May 3 (Folder 1, Box 1742)
      - Correspondence from Lowell Thomas to Mr. Leland. Measures 3 x 2¼ inches, 1961 March 29 (Folder 2, Box 1742)
      - Lowell Thomas broadcasting for CBS. Measures 3 x 4½ inches, undated (Folder 3, Box 1742)
      - Lowell Thomas standing by the fireplace at Quaker Hill. Measures 2¼ x 2¼ inches, circa 1960s (Folder 4, Box 1742)
      - Lowell Thomas standing next to a table. Measures 2¼ x 2¼ inches, undated (Folder 5, Box 1742)
      - Lowell Thomas surrounded by New Guinea village natives (High Adventure with Lowell Thomas). Measures 3¾ x 3¼ inches, 1957 (Folder 6, Box 1742)
      - Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. grasping a flag pole in Alaska. Measures 3¾ x 3¼ inches, circa 1950s (Folder 7, Box 1742)
      - Printing plate for “Out West.” Includes advertisements. Measures 3 x 2 inches, 1872 March 28 (Folder 8, Box 1742)
      - Christ Church, Quaker Hill. Measures 5 x 6½ inches, undated (Folder 9, Box 1742)
      - Lowell Thomas business card wrapped in blue protective paper. Typeface on paper reads “Mr. Lowell Thomas” and is stamped “24 March 1926”. Measures 2½ x 3½ inches, 1926 March 24 (Folder 10, Box 1742)
      - Brown Renault wine and champagne case (“Liberty and Prosperity”) that originally housed printing plates pertaining to Lawrence of Arabia or Allenby In Palestine and other miscellaneous items. Measures 12 x 14 x 4½ inches, undated (Folder 1, Box 1743)